<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Urbano Sheepdog – Agriculture</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/agriculture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agriculture on Urbano Sheepdog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/agriculture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Urbano Sheepdog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urbano Sheepdog&lt;/strong&gt; is a technology-based startup dedicated to developing solutions in &lt;strong&gt;AIoT (Artificial Intelligence of Things)&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;cybersecurity&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;smart devices&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;agriculture&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;defense&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;governments&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;smart cities&lt;/strong&gt;. Founded as &lt;strong&gt;Urbano Applied Research&lt;/strong&gt;, the company evolved into its new identity to reflect its core purpose: to act as a true &lt;em&gt;sheepdog&lt;/em&gt;, guarding the integrity, sovereignty, and intelligence of systems that connect the physical and digital worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mission&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#mission&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We design and implement technologies that integrate &lt;strong&gt;advanced sensors&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;edge computing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;embedded artificial intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;resilient infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;, with the goal of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting &lt;strong&gt;digital sovereignty and security&lt;/strong&gt; in connected technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabling &lt;strong&gt;automation and monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; for agriculture, with a focus on productivity, sustainability, and traceability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivering &lt;strong&gt;applied cyber defense&lt;/strong&gt;, protecting critical devices in sensitive operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supporting &lt;strong&gt;smart governance&lt;/strong&gt; by providing technology for data-driven public management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Areas of Expertise&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;areas-of-expertise&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#areas-of-expertise&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agriculture&lt;/strong&gt;: development of AIoT devices for climate, soil, and water resource monitoring; autonomous alert and response systems for pests and extreme events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defense and security&lt;/strong&gt;: prototyping of autonomous devices and embedded systems focused on tactical operations and critical infrastructure protection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governments and smart cities&lt;/strong&gt;: solutions for urban data collection and analysis, mobility, environmental management, and transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIoT cybersecurity&lt;/strong&gt;: creation of secure architectures for connected devices, emphasizing encryption, resilience against attacks, and regulatory compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Differentials&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;differentials&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#differentials&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End-to-end development&lt;/strong&gt;: from concept to functional prototype, in agile, iterative cycles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commitment to &lt;strong&gt;national technology&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;digital sovereignty&lt;/strong&gt; principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on &lt;strong&gt;low operational cost&lt;/strong&gt; solutions tailored to emerging markets and public sector needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vision&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;vision&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#vision&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To become a reference in Latin America for the development of secure, sovereign AIoT technologies, contributing to a future where &lt;strong&gt;technology and strategy work together to strengthen nations&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
